Michael Oluwasegun

Software Engineer

Address Ikotun, Lagos, Nigeria. Linked-In linkedin.com/in/micheal-oluwasegun-a6075518a

I am a software developer with a working experience of about 3years who has undergone a high level of professionalism with a core value of building remarkable, outstanding, quality, and excellent web solution. This software is made with neat, readable code implementation using a range of different recent technologies in order to deliver quality web software..

Skills

PHP (Framework: CodeIgniter & Laravel)

Very Good

NodeJS ●●●●

Very Good

JavaScript (Framework: Angular && Reactjs)

Very Good

Database server (SQL && NOSQL)

Very Good

HTML && CSS ●●●●

Very Good

Tools

Repositories (Github)

Text-editor (Visual studio code, Sublime text)

Operating system (Linux and Microsoft windows)

Server (Apache)

Postman

Work History

2019-07 - Full Stack Web Developer

Current Silicon Skies LTD, Egbeda, Lagos

As a full-stack web developer at Silicon Skies, I was a member of a team that constructed both the customer-facing and administrative sites for their client and in-house project. I was responsible for both front-end and back-

end development. We used a collection of

technologies for our underlying structures as the two projects were built together.

There, my knowledge of PHP, MYSQL, and JavaScript expanded; while I gained experience using core object-oriented PHP, MySQL databases queries. As a team, we practiced an Extreme programming (XP) methodology that included TDD (test-driven development), paired programming. As a member of this team, I also gained some experience in technical support.

LAMP (Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP)

JavaScript (Jquery)

HTML & CSS

2019-05 Full-Stack Web Developer

2019-06 Xwon, Ikeja, Lagos

Updating existing site with more modern designs and techniques.

Managed development milestones from initial steps through final delivery.

Improved and designed monitoring systems to address issues with system stability and quality of data.

2017-01 - Front End Developer

2019-04 Divrect, Lagos

As a Front-end Developer, I started out with a fresh course in Angular CLI and a review in JavaScript. While serving under a full-time Lead Web Developer, I was able to see the implementation of SPA (Single Page Application), the efficiency of Modern UI (User Interface) with readable code implementation. The intricacies revolving around application development have introduced me to the importance of modularized development.

Managed full-cycle design tasks, handling all phases from conception to completion while maintaining guidelines throughout.

Consuming API and incorporating responsive web techniques through the usage of Javascript, Angular, HTML, and CSS.

Increasing website performance using SEO best practices

Reviewed and tested customer-facing prototypes before deployment, applying best practice diagnostic techniques to verify usability.

Produced websites compatible with multiple browsers.

Designed and updated layouts to meet usability and performance requirements.

Completed full redesigns of existing websites to improve navigation, enhance visuals and strengthen search engine rankings.

Reviewed code to validate structures, assess security and verify browser, device and operating system compatibility.

Planned and engineered restful web services to manipulate dynamic datasets.

Employed coding practices based on commonly accepted standards to establish site layout and user interface.

Collaborated with in-house web designers to create sleek and innovative UI design.

2017-07- Instructor

2017-12 Amibba ICT Solution, Lagos

Teaching Software Engineering students to use various computer languages like PHP, Website Designing & Development, and specialist applications.

Eliminated process gaps by implementing new methods of standardized training.

Gathered and organized supplementary material to support structured lessons.

Tracked attendance and progress against goals for each participant. Scheduled and taught in class and coordinated slack channels to increase learning opportunities.

Documented student attendance and progress against goals. Spending contact time with students on an individual or group basis.

Applied various teaching aids to minimize learning gaps and instruct and motivate students.

Evaluated and revised lesson plans and course content to achieve student-centered learning.

Used learning assessments to regularly monitor student understanding of class concepts and materials.

Implemented and optimized new curriculum and day-to-day instruction to align educational strategies with industry best practices.

2017-01- System Upgrade

2017-06 Petro-tec Nig Ltd, Lagos

Carried out day to day duties accurately and efficiently.

Resolved problems, improved operations and provided exceptional service.

Increase customer satisfaction by resolving product and services issues.

Eliminated downtime and maximized revenue by providing top project quality control.

Education

2014-01-	National Diploma: Computer Science
2016-10	Benue State Polytechnic - Benue, Nigeria

2007-08- High School Diploma

2013-07 Green Pastures High School – Lagos, Nigeria